# Arseni Zhukau Software Engineer

# Summary

My main areas of interest lay in domains of backend development and data engineering. I have experience working on a data engineering and full stack developer positions. All of these makes me familiar with quite a broad set of different tools. I'm looking forward to apply my knowledge and strengthen it further.

## **Skills**

Languages

Python, Scala, TypeScript, SQL, C++

Machine Learning

Linear/logarithmic regression, KNN, decision trees, gradient boosting, etc.

**Technologies** 

Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, FastAPI, Django, DRF, SQLAlchemy, REST, Postman, React, React Query, Async, Git, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Scikit-learn, Hadoop, Map Reduce, MySQL, MS SQL Server, Postgres, MongoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Bash, Linux

## Experience

#### FullStack Developer, IBA Poland Oct 2022 – present

TypeScript, React, React Query, Axios, ChakraUI, Airflow REST API, Python, FastAPI, PyTest, SQLAIchemy, Postgres, Postman, GitLab

**Airflow UI.** This project required new functionality compered to default Airflow webserver UI for more strict privacy control and user specific features in dashboards with statistics for ETL support team. I developed a custom web interface for Airflow using React along with FastAPI server to extend standard Airflow REST API. Managed CI/CD pipelines on GitLab, deployed as a microservice in Kubernetes.

#### Data Engineer, IBA Feb 2022 - Oct 2022

Scala, Apache Spark, Apache Airflow, Docker, Kubernetes, IBM DB2, IBM Cloud Object Storage, Zeppelin Notebook

**Spark ETL pipelines.** Developed and performed deep investigation of Spark pipelines, configurations, and deployment options, gradually achieving huge performance improvements. Implemented scalable data generator in Scala to simulate the real data and upload it to IBM DB2 instance to use this data for transformation pipelines testing. Pipeline results are saved as a CSV in IBM Cloud Object Storage. Deployed on Kubernetes cluster using Apache Airflow for execution scheduling.

### Languages

English – B2, EF SET Polish – A2 Belarusian – Native Russian – Native

#### Courses

IsSoft Open Big Data School

Hadoop, Map Reduce, PySpark, SQL, Python, Docker, Zeppelin Notebook, Google Cloud

Rolling Scopes School Machine Learning and Data Science

Python, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Jupyter Notebook, etc.

LeverX Python Backend

Python, Django, Django Rest Framework, SQL

## **Education**

Bachelor, BSUIR, automated data processing systems

Belarus, Minsk, 2018-2022